

# **MOHAMMED SUHAIL**

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

+971 567440267

M suhail3k@gmail.com

www.suhaill.com



O Dubai, UAE

## **OBJECTIVE**

Self-motivated and hardworking Software Developer with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Application and 3 years of working experience. I'm seeking a key role in an organization where I can put my technical skills along with time management and team working capabilities into practice. I'm adept in PHP, Java, Laravel, Spring Boot and My SQL and have also worked on projects relevant to it. Also I possess strong work ethics and problem solving skills.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Software Developer**

Zone Delivery Services LLC - Dubai, UAE March 2021 to Present

- Working with PHP Laravel framework and Spring Boot for development of ERP and CRM software.
- Built REST APIs in Laravel and Spring Boot that served data to front-end to get the information.
- Collaborated with a team of software engineers to refactor the code and reduce the service loading time.
- Learned and working with platforms and technologies including API Management tools, AWS, Jira and Docker.
- Developed, tested, debugged and documented software applications.
- Gained proficiency in OOPs concepts.
- Ability to quickly learn and apply any new technologies.

#### **Software Engineer**

Quest Innovative Solutions (P) Ltd - Kerala, India July 2020 to January 2021

- Have successfully written HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Worked on back end with PHP, MySQL and Laravel framework.
- Implemented multiple projects based on Java and PHP.
- Research for new ideas and implementing them on projects.
- Meeting all tasks assigned by team lead.
- Working closely with team members.

#### **SKILLS**

HTML	••••
CSS	•••••
Javascript	••••
React	••••
Bootstrap	•••••
Jquery	••••
PHP	••••
Laravel	••••
Java	••••
Spring Boot	••••
Node Js	••••
MySQL	••••
MongoDB	••••
Git	••••

#### **PERSONAL**

Date of birth

05/06/1998

Photoshop

Marital Status

Single

**Driving License** 

Yes

# **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Computer Application (BCA)**

University of Calicut 2017 - 2020

## **Higher Secondary (Plus Two)**

Board of Kerala 2015 - 2017

## **Secondary Education (SSLC)**

Board of Kerala 2014 - 2015

## **LANGUAGES**

English

Malayalam

Hindi

## **PORTFOLIO**

www.suhaill.com

## www.suhaill.com